https://www.newcom.ca/privacy-policy

Skip to primary navigation Skip to main content Skip to footer
Collection, Use and Disclosure
Disclosure to Newcom; Disclosure as Permitted or Required by Law
GENERAL
Newcom Media Inc. and its affiliates (collectively, "Newcom" or "we") agree to maintain the privacy, security and accuracy of the Personal Information (as hereinafter defined) in accordance with applicable laws and the terms of this Privacy Policy.
This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose and safeguard the personal information that you or a third party provide. Providing personal information or authorizing a third party to disclose personal information to us signifies your consent to Newcom’s collection, use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you provide personal information to us about a third party or authorize a third party to disclose personal information to us, you agree that you were authorized to do so.
ACCOUNTABILITY
Newcom is responsible for Personal Information and has designated a person responsible for Newcom’s privacy compliance (“Designated Privacy Person”) to ensure compliance with this Privacy Policy and applicable privacy laws. If you have any concerns, questions, requests or complaints about this Privacy Policy or the processing of your Personal Information, please contact our Designated Privacy Person by email at pat@newcom.ca.
Alternatively, you can contact our Designated Privacy Person by mail at:
Newcom Media Inc.
Attention: Privacy Officer
5353 Dundas Street West, Suite 400
Toronto, ON
M9B 6H8
COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Personal Information
For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means information that can identify an individual directly or through other reasonably available means. Personal Information does not include business contact information that is used for the purpose of communicating or facilitating communication with an individual in relation to their employment, business, or profession. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary herein, the meaning of Personal Information shall be interpreted in a manner that conforms with the minimum requirements of applicable privacy legislation.
Collection, Use and Disclosure
The types of Personal Information that we may collect from time to time may include your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, contact details, financial, credit or billing information, demographic details, and other personally identifiable information.
Some of our services, websites, and apps require you to register. Newcom may ask you for some personal identifying information in order to create an account (typically e-mail address and/or a password for your account).
When you register for one of our products (site membership, trade show attendance, newsletter subscriptions, etc.), our forms may ask for contact and demographic information. This information is used to allow you to access certain areas of our services, websites and apps that send permission-based products and services to you (that are based on the demographic information), and to advise you of other Newcom products and services. In addition, demographic information may be used: (i) to customize the display of our services, websites, and apps to you by showing content that we think might be of interest or related to your past visits; and (ii) as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.
Personal Information may be collected through your voluntary disclosure, use of our service, apps, or websites, purchase of our products, subscription to our publications, completion of registration or subscription forms, by means of surveys, entry to a contest or other promotion or through third-party agents, contractors, vendors or suppliers who provide products and services to us ("Service Providers"), as well as through our third-party business partners to whom we provide our products and services.
For the purpose of maintaining quality service, telephone calls to our customer service lines may be recorded. If your call is subject to a quality assurance program, you will be so advised prior to speaking with a representative.
We collect, use and/or disclose your Personal Information for purposes reasonably connected to why you’ve provided it to us, as well as for purposes otherwise permitted or required by law. Some examples of purposes for which we use personal information include the following:
to create and maintain client accounts;
to provide the product, service or information you requested;
to communicate with you regarding the products and services you requested and to respond to your requests and inquiries;
to process payments and collect unpaid accounts;
to offer you tailored content, including advertisements and promotions;
to assist you when you contact our customer support services, including to direct your questions to appropriate individuals, investigate and address any of your concerns, and to improve and monitor our customer support responses;
to detect and protect against error, fraud, theft and other illegal activity;
to better understand your needs and preferences and to improve our products and services;
to engage in business transactions;
to provide information to our employees, contractors, and affiliates to allow them to perform services on our behalf;
to organize and administer contests and/or surveys;
to inform you of special offers and promotions;
to comply generally with applicable laws and all other applicable regulatory requirements; and/or
for any other purpose for which you otherwise give your consent, including as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy.
We share non-personal, aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, demographics, traffic patterns, and related site information with advertisers and reputable third-party vendors for marketing and promotional purposes; however, none of the information we disclose in this aggregate form can be used to personally identify you.
Disclosure to Newcom; Disclosure as Permitted or Required by Law
We may: (i) share your personal information with our affiliates; (ii) combine information internally across our affiliates or our different products, services, websites, and apps; and (iii) combine personal information with demographic information, publicly available records and other third-party information sources. We may use this information to provide you with a customized experience, to improve the quality of our products, services, websites, and apps, and to promote and develop products, websites, services, and apps of Newcom, or as otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy.
When you provide Personal Information to us with respect to employment opportunities, including, but not limited to, your resume, we will treat such Personal Information on a confidential basis and use it only: (i) to consider you for current or future employment opportunities within Newcom; and (ii) to contact you with respect to such employment opportunities. We will retain your Personal Information for further employment opportunities that may arise within Newcom, unless you inform us that you no longer want us to retain your information.
We may provide Personal Information in response to a court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain Personal Information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property and safety of others and ourselves.
Disclosure to Service Providers
Newcom has operations in both Canada and the United States, as well as in other jurisdictions. We may transfer your Personal Information to Service Providers acting on our behalf for purposes mentioned in this Privacy Policy. Note that some of our Service Providers who process or handle Personal Information on our behalf may be located in the United States and other jurisdictions outside of Ontario and outside of Canada. You acknowledge and agree that, as a result, your Personal Information may be processed, used, stored or accessed in other jurisdictions and may be subject to the laws of those jurisdictions. For example, information may be disclosed in response to valid demands or requests from government authorities, courts, or law enforcement in other countries.
Disclosure in Business Transactions
Newcom may be involved in the proposed or actual sale, merger, financing, securitization, insuring or restructuring of some or all of its business or assets. In the course of such transactions, Newcom may disclose your Personal Information to applicable third parties who request such information for the purposes of evaluating or performing the proposed transactions. In such cases, Newcom will require such third parties to agree to protect the privacy of your Personal Information in accordance with applicable privacy laws. Our successors and assigns may collect, use and disclose your Personal Information for substantially the same purposes as those set out in this Privacy Policy.
CONSENT
We collect, use and disclose your Personal Information with your consent or as permitted or required by applicable law. Your consent may be express or implied, depending on the circumstances and applicable laws. By providing Personal Information to us you are consenting to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Information about another person to us, we assume you have obtained the valid consent of such individual to enable us to collect, use or disclose such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Note that if you withdraw your consent to certain uses of your Personal Information, we may not be able to provide you with certain of our services or products.
UNSUBSCRIBE
Any electronic communication that we send you, whether on our behalf or on behalf of our third-party business partners, will include instructions on how to unsubscribe from any such future communications. If you do not consent, please do not provide your Personal Information or, where applicable, exercise opt-out options offered, or send an e-mail to privacy@newcom.ca.
PRIVACY PROTECTION AND OUR WEBSITES
Cookies
By using a browser feature called a "cookie" and other methods (including tracking pixels, also known as web beacons and log files), Newcom and our third-party Service Providers may gather non-personal information and Personal Information when you visit our websites, services, or apps, such as data about the frequency of your visits to our websites, the duration of your visits, the number of pages you view and the type of Internet browser and operating system you use, the date and time of your query, and your browser language. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that identifies the visitor’s browser, but not necessarily the visitor, each time our websites, services, or apps are visited. As part of our email communications and website analyses, we may use web beacons and track URLs. Web beacons are electronic files that count users who access a website or page and can also allow us to see if a cookie has been activated. Web beacons on web pages or email communications allow us to see how successful an article may be or that an email message was successfully delivered and read. Tracked URLs will count the amount of clicks on a web page. This allows us to edit a web page according to the popularity of the articles you read.
We may use this information for purposes including remembering your preferences and settings, providing personalized content, determining the popularity of certain content, authenticating users, determining the effectiveness of any advertising campaigns, and analyzing the behaviour and interests of people (including traffic and trends) accessing our website, services, and apps. We may also allow others to provide analytics services (e.g. Google Analytics) and audience measurement services for us, to serve advertisements on our behalf on the Internet, and to monitor and report on the performance of those advertisements.
Newcom and our third-party Service Providers may also use cookies, web beacons, log files, and other similar technologies to deliver interest-based advertisements that are relevant and targeted to the visitors of our websites.
You can manage your cookies by installing a third-party program or by reconfiguring your web browser. Most web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies; however, you can delete or disable cookies by modifying your settings. If you decide to disable cookies on our services, apps, and websites, you may not be able to take full advantage of all features of our services, apps, and websites.
Public Forums
Some of Newcom’s websites, apps, and services offer chat rooms and other public forums. If you post a review, make a comment, or otherwise submit Personal Information on a public forum such as social media accounts or public forums on our websites, services, or apps, your communications may be viewable by the public.
Searches
For your convenience, search functions are sometimes provided on our websites. We keep records of the words searched to learn more about what kind of information our visitors are seeking, and thus improve our products and services.
Hyperlinks
For your convenience, Newcom’s websites, services, and apps may contain hyperlinks to websites operated by third parties. When you click on one of these hyperlinks, you will be connected to a third-party site, which may have different privacy policies and practices in place. This Privacy Policy is no longer applicable when you leave our websites. You should consult the privacy policies of these other entities before providing any Personal Information on their websites. Newcom is not responsible, nor do we accept any liability, for the Personal Information collection, use and disclosure practices of other entities to which our websites, services, or apps may link.
Individuals Under 18
No Personal Information should be submitted or posted on our websites, services, or apps by individuals under 18 years of age without their parent’s or legal guardian’s permission. We may request the Personal Information of an individual under 18 years of age for contest administration purposes. In the event we do so, we will request such individual’s parent or legal guardian to consent prior to collecting such information.
SECURITY
Newcom has implemented security measures designed to safeguard the Personal Information under our care or control. Any Personal Information maintained by Newcom is archived in a secured environment based on the nature of the information.
Credit card information is processed using industry-standard encryption technology. Newcom limits the collection of Personal Information to that which is necessary for the purpose(s) identified by Newcom unless otherwise required or permitted by law. Credit card information submitted to Newcom will be used only to complete the purchase and arrange for shipping (where applicable) and/or for credit verification purposes (where applicable). Our security policies and procedures are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary.
Only authorized employees, agents, partners and Service Providers may have access to Personal Information under our care or control. We instruct all of our authorized employees, agents, partners and Service Providers who have access to Personal Information to use appropriate privacy and security precautions when processing such information.
ACCURACY AND ACCESS
We use reasonable efforts to ensure that your Personal Information is kept as accurate, complete and up-to-date as possible. In order to help us maintain and ensure that your Personal Information is accurate and up-to-date, please inform us as soon as possible of any changes so that we can update our records.
If you wish to request access to your Personal Information under our care or control, or make changes to it, please send your request in writing to our Designated Privacy Person at the address or numbers indicated above. In all cases, requests to access information or to change information will be treated in accordance with applicable laws.
CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
Newcom reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Any such changes will be posted on Newcom’s websites and will take effect immediately upon posting. We will take reasonable measures to advise affected individuals of any material changes, if necessary. You may contact our Designated Privacy Person at the address or numbers indicated above to obtain an up-to-date copy of this Privacy Policy.
GOVERNING LAW
This Privacy Policy and all related matters shall be interpreted and construed in accordance with the laws of the Province of Ontario and the applicable federal laws of Canada.
Last revised: 02/01/2020
© 2020 Newcom Media Inc.
